BDD stands for Behaviour Driven Development
But what does that mean?
What does it mean to do BDD?
BDD is a way for software teams to work
that closes the gap
between business people
and technical people by:
Encouraging collaboration across roles
to build shared understanding of
the desired behaviour of the system
Producing system documentation that
guides development
and is automatically checked against
the system’s behaviour
Working in rapid, small iterations to
increase feedback and the flow of value
Doing BDD involves doing these
three things over and over again:
First, you take a small upcoming change
to the system
like a User Story
and have a conversation to explore,
discover, and agree
on the details of how we want the
system to behave
using concrete examples
Next, you document those examples
in a way that could be automated
and check for agreement
Finally, you actually get coding and
implement the behaviour described
by each documented example
starting with an automated test
to guide the development of the code.
We call these practices Discovery
Formulation and Automation.
The idea is to make each change small
and iterate rapidly
moving back up a level each time you
need more information
Every time you automate and implement
a new example
you’ve added something
valuable to your system
and you’re ready to respond to feedback
Over time, the documented examples
become an asset
that enables your team to continue
confidently and rapidly making
changes to the system.
We call this “living documentation”,
because the code reflects the documentation,
and the documentation reflects the team’s
shared understanding
of what the code does
This shared understanding
and the living documentation
is constantly evolving.
Cucumber is a tool that facilitates BDD
We can’t teach you about Cucumber
without teaching you about BDD too
So, that’s where we’re going to start