Let's imagine we're building a
point-of-sale system for an electronics retailer
Dixies
Here's our next user story!
Process Refunds
In order to satisfy
customers statutory rights
As a sales assistant
I need to be able to process refunds
In order to prepare this story for
development we have what we call
a three amigos meeting
We call it the three amigos
because it involves
three different disciplines from the team
Test
Development
and Product
Let's watch one in action
The business rules to this story
are really simple
Any item can be returned within 14 days
as long as the customer has a receipt
Can you give me an example?
Okay
Collin the customer bought
a kettle last week from us
When he got home he realised the colour
didn't match his kitchen cabinets
and he really didn't like it
Um, he's brought it back to
the store for refund
He walks up to Sally
a junior sales assistant
and he asks her to process the refund
What's the outcome here?
What are we supposed to test?
Well we need to increment the
stock quantity for that item
so we know it's back in our inventory
Ah right, anything else?
No, no, I think that's all
What if Collin doesn't have his receipt?
Does Sally have to send him home?
Well, a manager can process a refund
with any proof of purchase
Collin could use a bank statement
for example?
But Sally can't do that so
she would have to ask her boss
Right, so there are two rules here:
The customer must have
proof of purchase, not just a receipt
and if they don't have their receipt
then it must be authorized
by a manager, right?
Oh, oh right! Exactly!
Aren't we forgetting something here?
Isn't Collin supposed to get his money back?
Oh! Uh, oh yes of course!
And does the system need to notify
anyone in the warehouse to
come pick up the kettle?
Good idea, Tammy.
Yes, I think that's out of our scope
for this version of the story
but I'll put it on the
backlog for future iteration