Once all three amigos are happy
that they understand the story
then you can start translating your
examples into something that
Cucumber can understand
Here's one of our examples
written out in Gherkin
the specification language for Cucumber
As you can see
Gherkin's almost like plain English
We have to use a few special key words
so that Cucumber can understand it, too
Words like Feature, Scenario,
Given, When, and Then
You'll learn all about these soon
We can refine as many examples
as we need into this form
to create an executable specification
for our software
In the next lesson
you'll learn how to create
your first Cucumber scenario
and execute it
Captions created by Jayson Smith for Cucumber Ltd.